after the powergate dual rectifier is
installed the mosfet based dual diodes
effectively starve the alternator of the
voltage it needs to turn on and start
producing power
to resolve this perfect switch uses an
alternator excitation circuit which is
triggered by the starter motor
when engine cranking is complete the
alternator excitation circuit turns on
[Music]
we momentarily turn off power blocking
between the main battery in the upstream
alternator
[Music]
with battery voltage present the
alternator's regulator instantly excites
causing power generation
power flows from the alternator through
the dual rectifier to the downstream
batteries
once the dual rectifier senses
alternator voltage rising the excitation
circuit turns off and the default power
blocking firmware takes over
with the engine off each battery can be
independently discharged
discharge of the auxiliary battery does
not affect the main battery
[Music]
main battery discharge does not affect
the auxiliary battery
when loads are applied to the auxiliary
battery the dual rectifier will not
allow current from the main battery to
feed auxiliary battery loads
current wants to flow from main to
auxiliary but the mosfet-based ideal
diode will not allow current to pass
[Music]
when loads are applied to the main
battery the dual rectifier will not
allow current from the auxiliary battery
to feed main battery loads
again the mosfet-based ideal diode will
not allow current to pass
if the main battery is discharged and
causes a no start condition the battery
combined feature can be used to transfer
energy from the auxiliary battery to the
main battery for self-jumping